Maria Olivia Robles

Graphic Design





🚷 (623) 986-4925 🔘 morobles.design@gmail.com 📵 behance.net/morobles 💡 Marina del rey,CA





SUMMARY

Accomplished graphic designer with 9+ years of experience developing brand and corporate collateral materials for print, online and offline marketing projects. Ability to produce creative analysis and implement effective design solutions for client improvement. Proven ability to collaborate effectively working under deadlines and adaptable to changing environments.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MARCH 2012 - PRESENT

MORA Studio88

FREELANCE GRAPHIC DESIGNER Marina del Rey, California

- Prepare digital files for pre-press, color correct and resolution.
- Work with print vendors to outsource large and specialty print jobs.
- Create designs, logos, layouts, and marketing material from scratch.
- Clients I Collaborated: Granite Dude, Tipyco Hats, Knullzcorp Inc., 101 Polo Club, Scottsdale Music & Entertainment.
- Applied knowledge of production to create high-quality results.
- Handled dual-language client communication solutions.
- Executed client materials for 3+ high-demand projects simultaneously.
- Contributed design ideas in early planning stages with customers and project managers.

MARCH 2019 - PRESENT

REMOTE - GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Everything Etched

Scottsdale, Arizona

- Collaborate with marketing to archive better advertising for local businesses.
- Clients I Collaborated: Wedding MBA convention Las Vegas, BUJÓRI Skincare.
- · Follow quality standards and procedures to minimize errors and maximize customer satisfaction.
- Plataforms used for sells Etsy, Shopify.
- · Operate with high integrity, built trust, and earned sustained credibility with internal and external clients.
- Generate new business leads through direct customer engagement, developing and optimizing informative content.
- Support with administrative tasks as needed.

JULY 2018 - MARCH 2019

IN-HOUSE - GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Everything Etched

Scottsdale, Arizona

- · Close relationship with customers to present mockups and collect information for adjustments, establish scopes and manage all phases trough out the project devvelopment.
- Develop a creative design for in-house marketing, including print materials, brochures, banners and signs.
- Clients I Collaborated: U-haul, VCA Animal Hospitals, Soilworks, CMC design, Vegas Golden Knights, JW Marriott Scottsdale Camelback, Wild Sky Aircraft, The 808 team.
- Offer pricing and provide recommendations to clients.
- Ability to take on various roles including graphics design and customer service to provide range across projects.
- Provide observations, take measurements and perform tests at several stages of the project.

EXPERIENCE

PROFESSIONAL JUNE 2016 - JULY 2018 BTC Southwest

Typesetter / Graphic Designer Tempe, Arizona

- Managed execution of 200+ pre-press orders daily.
- · Clients I Collaborated: Office Max, Discount Tire, The Paper Place AZ, ON Semiconductor, Terros health, High School Unified District, Four Peaks.
- Ensure consistency in design according to brand guidelines while enforcing brand standards and proper format for production.
- Implemented proper client style guide revisions and internal updates.
- Developed product design brand assets and client solutions.
- Developed print materials such as brochures, banners and signs and packaging materials to support product branding strategies.

MAY 2010 - DECEMBER 2015 GRAPHIC DESIGNER

Label and Printing Solutions Chandler, Arizona

- Managed internal sales communication for 7+ high-end clients.
- · Clients I Collaborated: Cafe Valley, Natural Delight, Denmark Foods, Doctor Hummus.
- Stores: Costco, Fry's, Bashas, Safeway, Sprouts.
- · Designed daily image for manipulation projects.
- Regulated FDA protocol standards for company manufactured.
- Verified proper completion of all outgoing client deliverables.
- · Retouched, enhanced and color-corrected vector product images.
- Strong experience in retail with full understanding of wholesale needs collaborating with retail marketing and visual merchandising.

EDUCATION

DECEMBER 2016

ARIZONA STATE UNIVERSITY - Tempe, Arizona Ira A. Fulton Schools of Engineering BAS, Graphic Information Technology

MAY 2014

SCOTTSDALE COMMUNITY COLLEGE - Scottsdale, Arizona AAS, Graphic Design

2010

PRINT EXCELLENCE CERTIFICATE AWARD Printing Industries of Arizona and New Mexico

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH, SPANISH, PORTUGUESE

SKILLS

Adobe Creative Suite: Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign, Lightroom, Dreamweaver

Platforms: Windows / Mac Os

Photography (DSLR), Html, Quickbooks, Shopify, Etsy Microsoft Office Suite: Word, Excel, Powerpoint